Privacy Policy
--------------

DWSNET s.r.l. (“from now on, for the sake of brevity, “DWService”, or the “Company”) informs you that your personal data acquired while browsing DWService’s web site will be processed in accordance with the law on the protection of personal data.

With reference to the methods used for the management and processing of your personal data, DWService provides you with the following information pursuant to Article 13 of EU Regulation No. 679/2016:

### 1\. Types of data collected, purposes and legal basis for the processing operations

#### Browsing data

The information technology systems and software procedures that enable the functionality of this web site acquire, during their normal utilization, certain personal data that is implicitly transmitted to the Company because of the use of internet communication protocols.

This category of data includes:

* the IP addresses or domain names of the computers used to access the site;
* the MAC (Media Access Control) addresses;
* the addresses in URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) notation of the requested resources;
* the time of the request;
* the method used to submit the request to the server;
* the size of the file obtained in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the response given by the server (success, error, etc.);
* other parameters relating to the operating system and the user’s information technology environment;

These data are used for the sole purposes of compiling anonymous statistical information on the use of DWService’s web site and to check its correct functionality, and are deleted immediately after processing.

The legal basis that legitimizes the processing of personal data for this purpose is set out in Article 6, section 1, letter b) of EU Regulation No. 679/2016 – i.e. processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.

These personal data may be also used to ascertain liability in the event of cybercrimes that cause damage to the site. The legal basis that legitimizes the processing of personal data for this purpose is set out in the circumstances described by Article 6, section 1, letter f) of EU Regulation No. 679/2016 – i.e. processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims of whenever courts are acting in their judicial capacity.

Lastly, the same data may also be used to ensure compliance with legal obligations or requests on the part of the judicial authorities. The legal basis that legitimizes the processing of personal data for this purpose is set out in Article 6, section 1, letter c) of EU Regulation No. 679/2016 – i.e. processing is necessary to comply with a legal obligation to which the Data Controller is subject.

#### Data that you supply voluntarily

Should you send email messages to the email addresses found on the DWService’s web site, DWService may process your email address (as the sender) and any additional personal data contained in the message, in order to respond, again by email, to the requests you have submitted. The legal basis that legitimizes the processing of personal data for this purpose is set out in Article 6, section 1, letter b) of EU Regulation No. 679/2016 – i.e. processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.

The same data may also be used to ensure compliance with legal obligations or requests from judicial authorities. The legal basis that legitimizes the processing of personal data for this purpose is set out in Article 6, section 1, letter c) of EU Regulation No. 679/2016 – i.e. processing is necessary to comply with a legal obligation to which the Data Controller is subject.

#### Cookies

DWService’s web site uses technical (session and browsing) cookies for the purposes of enabling the normal browsing and utilization of the website (allowing, for example, authentication in order to access reserved areas). For the complete information relating to the processing operations carried out on personal data through cookies, please see the full cookies statement, which can be reached on every page of the portal.

### 2\. Data retention period

Any personal data that is collected and processed as a result of your browsing this site will be stored for the duration of the service delivery and then immediately deleted or anonymized. Any personal data that you submit through the tools of the site will be deleted after the requested service is provided or a response is given, and in any case within the maximum period of 2 years from the completion of those operations, except for the data that is necessary to ensure compliance with fiscal, accounting and administrative regulations, or to fulfill other legal obligations, and to document the operations performed.

### 3\. Processing methods and security measures

Any personal data collected will be processed, retained and analyzed using electronic tools and will be stored both in electronic format and in hard copy, organized into databases, and on any other appropriate type of media.

Specific security measures are implemented to prevent the loss, illegal or unfair use of the data, or unauthorized access to them. The list of implemented security measures is available in the [Security](https://www.dwservice.net/security.html) section of the site.

The processing of your personal data carried out by DWService does not involve any automated decision-making.

### 4\. Disclosure of your personal data

The disclosure of the browsing data is required in order to supply the requested service (browsing of the site) and it is, therefore, compulsory for that purpose. Failure to provide personal data will make it impossible for DWService to allow you to browse this site.

The disclosure of user’s data for other purposes is optional: failure to provide personal data will not have consequences for the data subject but it may make it impossible to provide you with the requested responses.

### 5\. Parties to which your personal data may be disclosed

None of your personal data collected by the Company will be disclosed indiscriminately, but may be communicated to those parties that have the right to access your personal data to ensure compliance with legal and secondary and/or EU regulations (for example, to Authorities in the framework of judicial cooperation), and to the Data Controller’s own personnel, and also to companies, associations or professional firms that provide services and operations on behalf of the Data Controller, operating as Data Processors, in particular for the provision of ICT services (e.g. web hosting services), to ensure compliance with legal obligations, and for every other organisational and/or administrative requirement that is necessary to provide the requested services.

The names of the parties, operating as Data Processors, to which your personal data may be disclosed are shown in an up-to-date list that can be requested from DWService (through the contact information indicated at Point 9).

### 6\. Transfer of data outside the European Economic Area or to international organizations

DWService does not transfer personal data collected through its website outside the European Economic Area (EEA) or to international organizations. In exceptional cases, solely for the purpose of complying with legal obligations to which it is subject, DWService may transfer personal data to foreign Public Authorities (e.g. to United States of America's Authorities). In these cases, the transfer of data outside the EEA will only take place in the presence of relevant reasons of public interest, as provided for in art. 49, par. 1, lett. d) Reg. EU n. 679/2016, and in compliance with the additional applicable data protection laws.

### 7\. Links to third-party websites or services

This privacy notice is provided only for the processing of personal data carried out through DWService’s web site and not for other websites that may be visited by the user via links, which act as independent data controllers. Therefore, users are invited to carefully read the privacy policies of third-party services before accessing them. All information regarding the processing of data by YouTube can be found in its [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

### 8\. Your rights as the Data Subject

In relation to the aforementioned processing operations carried out on your personal data, you are entitled to exercise at all times those rights set out by EU Regulation No. 679/2016 (GDPR), including, for example, the right to be informed within 30 days from your request as to:

* the origin of any personal data held that concern you;
* the purposes and methods of the processing operations;
* the logic applied in the case of processing operations carried out using electronic instruments;
* the identification of the Data Controller, the Data Processors and the designated representative;

As the Data Subject, you have the right to obtain, within the same timeframe of 30 days:

* access to the data and its updating, rectification or (where in your interest) completion;
* the erasure, transformation into anonymous form or blocking of access to any data processed in breach of the law;
* the limitation of the processing of those data that concern you, or to request the reduction of the purposes and/or methods for/with which your data are being processed to the Data Controller or the Data Processor.

You can also request a copy of your data in a standard format (the so-called “Right to data portability”).

**As the Data Subject, you also have the right to object, at any time and at no cost, wholly or partially:**

* **for legitimate reasons, to processing of your personal data, even if the processing operations are still relevant to the purpose for which the data were collected in the first place;**
* **to processing of your personal data carried out pursuant to Article 6, Paragraph 1 of the GDPR, Letter e. (“processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller”) or f. (“processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party”) including profiling on the basis of these provisions;**
* **to processing of your personal data for the purposes of sending advertising or direct sales material or for the completion of market research or commercial communications (direct marketing), including any relevant profiling operations.**

You have the right to withdraw your consent for the processing operations when that consent is based on by Article 6, Paragraph 1, Letter a. (when “the data subject has given consent to the processing of his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes”), or by Article 9, Paragraph 2, Letter a. (when “the data subject has given explicit consent to the processing of those personal data for one or more specified purposes”) of EU Regulation No. 679/2016, at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.

In particular, the data subject, in order to no longer receive marketing communication may, at any time, request free cancellation from the service by sending a message to the contact data indicated in point 9 of this privacy policy.

Should you consider the processing operations to have been carried out in breach of current legislation, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, specifically in the Member State in which you habitually reside or work, or the Member State where the alleged breach has taken place. The Italian supervisory authority can be contacted using the contact data on its [own website](https://www.garanteprivacy.it/).

### 9\. Data Controller – Contact data

The Data Controller is DWSNET s.r.l. with its registered offices at via Fedro n. 16, 80122 Napoli, VAT n. IT10018841212.

The Company can also be contacted at the email address [support@dwservice.net](mailto:support@dwservice.net).

You can submit a request to exercise any of the rights listed above by writing to the following email address: [support@dwservice.net](mailto:support@dwservice.net).
